What? You want to see him?
Yeah.
Why do you want to see him?
There's nothing interesting about him.
That's right. It's a waste of time.
Just tell me!
I heard that he's here.
The Shinigami who went down
to the Human World
and did some interesting things.
Who is it?
I've come to see you.
I want you to tell me your story.
Story?
I won't ask you to do it for free.
I would have liked it
if it was a little juicier...
I want to go to the lower world.
I'm sick of this stagnant world.
I heard that the Human World is fun.
It's no fun watching guys
who complain about a dull world.
It's fun watching a guy
who foolishly thinks that...
he can change the world.
Fine. I was getting bored, anyway.
I'll tell you my story.
This is for that gross apple.
This is a story of a human...
who tried to change the world
and become God.
Someone's got to do it...
Things are no good as they are!
Each day... repeats... itself.
It would be better for the world
if everyone was dead!
That's right. The world is corrupt.
Those who are corrupt
are better off dead!
I'm going to... change the world...
with the Death Note!
I'm going to wipe out evildoers.
Yes, I'm cleansing the world!
Those who have committed
terrible crimes...
will succumb to heart attacks...
Even an idiot will be able to figure out
that someone is behind it.
I'm going to let everyone
know of my existence!
The power to fight evil!
Justice served!
If I do that, the world will be
a better place.
And I will create a world populated
only by kind, honest people
who have received my approval.
And I...
will become
the god of the new world.
Death Note: Relight
Visions of a God
Really? You went to see that?
It was a real waste of time.
I want to get my money back.
Death Note...
Directly translated,
it means "notebook of death."
"How to use..."
"Those whose names are
written in this notebook will die."
How silly...
This is really sick...
This isn't any better than
a chain letter...
"Those whose names are written
in this notebook will die"?
Jeez... something's wrong
with me, too...
Welcome home!
You're home early, Light.
Yeah.
I'm home. Mom.
Oh... The results of
the national mock exam?
Quickly!
Here.
Oh my, number one again!
You really worked hard,
didn't you, Light?!
Yeah.
Well, I'm going to be studying,
so don't bother me.
All right.
Oh, Light. Do you want anything?
I'll get you whatever you want.
Nothing in particular, Mom.
I already have what I want...
I see you like it.
Why are you so surprised?
I'm Ryuk, a Shinigami.
I'm the one who dropped
that notebook.
Judging by the way you were acting...
I think you already know that
that's no ordinary notebook.
A Shinigami, huh..?
I'm not surprised, Ryuk.
No...
I've been waiting for you, Ryuk...
Oh?
I've had my doubts whether
the Shinigami notebook was real...
But after seeing all sorts of things,
I'm confident in my actions...
I see... You surprise me...
I've heard that the Death Note
has appeared in the Human World
many times in the past.
But you're the first who's done
this much in just five days.
Most people would have been too scared
to write this many names...
I'm prepared, Ryuk.
I used the notebook
with the knowledge
that it belonged to a Shinigami.
And now a Shinigami has come...
What are you going to do to me?
Are you going to take my soul?
Hm? What are you talking about?
Is that what humans think we're like?
I won't do anything to you.
As soon as the notebook
lands in the Human World.
it becomes a part of it.
In other words.
it belongs to you.
It's... mine..?
If you don't want it,
pass it to another human.
When you do,
I'll erase your memories of it.
Then there really is no price
for using the Death Note?
If anything... the pain and fear
that only someone who used
the Death Note would know...
And when you die...
I'll write your name
in my notebook...
Don't think that someone
who's used the Death Note
can go to heaven or hell.
That's all.
Look forward to that when you die.
This week alone. there have been
52 victims that we know of.
They all died of heart attacks.
There are probably some criminals
whose deaths aren't confirmed.
- They were all criminals who...
- It's already started, Bureau Chief.
probably would have been executed.
- Yeah, I had a call from headquarters.
- Perhaps we shouldn't concern ourselves.
How stupid!
It doesn't matter if they're major criminals
or death row inmates.
Murder is murder.
We aren't sure that
it was murder yet.
How can over a hundred people dying
of heart attacks be a coincidence?!
There's nothing we can learn
from the way they've died.
I agree! It would be different if
they had been stabbed with knifes!
We have to get L to help us!
Bureau Chief. who's L?
Oh, this is your first time at
an Interpol meeting, isn't it?
No one knows L's name,
location, or even what he looks like.
Furthermore. he solves
any case no matter how difficult.
He's solved many of
the world's unsolved cases.
He's one of the world's secret elite
and last hope...
Something like that...
But L is an arrogant person
who only takes cases he's interested in!
That's right.
And we have no way of contacting him!
L is already on the move.
L has already begun
to investigate this case.
W-Watari...
Huh? Watari..?
The only man who can contact L.
Of course. no one knows
Watari's identity either...
Please be silent.
I shall let you hear L's voice
right now.
Members of Interpol...
I am L.
The Legend of Kira the Savior...
That's pretty cool...
Are they referring to you?
Yeah. it seems "Kira" comes
from the word "killer."
I don't really like that...
But the world already
knows me as Kira.
If you do an internet search on Kira,
you'll find thousands of pages like this.
Television and newspapers
have only reported
The Deepening Mystery...
A Sensation is Called Accident
Reconsidering the Investigative System
Mysterious Deaths Continue
the successive bizarre deaths
of vicious criminals.
But everyone in
the world can sense it.
That there's someone
who's seeking justice.
Oh?
This is good...
Everything's going according
to plan.
We interrupt our program
to bring you
a special live broadcast
from Interpol.
Huh? What's this?
Interpol..?
We're about to begin.
I am Lind L. Taylor,
the only person who can move
the entire world's police.
I am otherwise known as "L."
Wh-Who is he..?
It's finally begun...
Someone has been systematically
murdering criminals.
This is unforgivable.
It is one of the greatest
criminal acts in history.
Therefore, I intend to apprehend
the person responsible for these crimes...
the person known as "Kira."
He says he's going to catch you.
What an idiot.
He can't catch me.
I have a Death Note.
As long as I have this notebook,
I won't leave any proof behind.
It's impossible to catch me.
The police are getting involved
and this guy making an appearance...
Everything's going according to plan.
Kira, I have a pretty good idea of
why you're doing this.
But what you're doing is evil!
I'm evil?
I am justice!
I protect the weak who fear evil.
I am the man who
will become...
the god of the ideal, new world!
And all those who oppose this god...
are evil!
You're too foolish. L...
It would have been
a little more interesting
if you'd have been
a little smarter...
I'll show you what happens
if you defy me...
The whole world is watching, L.
Five more seconds.
4... 3... 2... 1...
What's wrong?
Why don't you say something?!
Unbelievable...
I was just testing to make sure,
but I didn't think it was possible...
Kira... you can kill by indirect means...
Had I not seen it with my own eyes,
I would have never believed it.
Listen closely, Kira.
If you have killed the man
on your screen, Lind L. Taylor,
you just killed a man who was
to be executed today at this time.
Not me.
What..?!
It hasn't been reported
on television or the internet.
He's a criminal that the police
caught in secret.
Even you weren't able
to gather information on him.
He tricked you.
But I... L, do exist!
Now try to kill me!
Th-That bastard..!
What's wrong?
- Hurry up and do it!
- What is this?! This is incredible!
- Quickly! Try to kill me!
- Are you trying to get yourself killed, L?!
What's going on?!
What's wrong?
Kill me right now!
- Kill me right now!
- It's Kira versus L!
Can't you do it?
It seems that you can't kill me...
There are some people
you can't kill...
You've given me a good hint.
In return, I'll tell you
something interesting.
I said that this broadcast was
being aired live around the world...
But actually, was only broadcast
in Japan's Kanto region.
I was planning on airing this broadcast
in other regions at different times,
but it seems that there's no need
for that anymore.
You're in Kanto right now.
L's pretty good.
I never thought that things
would go quite so well.
But, Kira, it seems that it might
not be too long till I get you executed.
I knew it... L is just as
I had expected he would be...
Yes. He's proved Kira's existence,
that the killings took place,
and that Kira's in Japan...
Kira, I'm very interested in
what method you use to kill.
But I'll find that out...
...when I catch you.
Until we meet again, Kira.
Light, do you have a minute?
Ryuk, I told you not to talk
to me outside.
How many times do I have
to remind you?
Then I'll just talk to you.
Close your ears if
you don't want to listen.
Someone's been following you
for a while now.
I'm L.
This man is?
He looks different from
what I imagined...
I'm Yagami of the Police Department.
Oh. I'm Matsuda.
I'm Aizawa.
I'm Mogi.
I'm Ukita.
I'm sorry we're late.
These five are the current...
Wha..?!
What are you doing?!
You'd be dead if I were Kira.
Mr. Soichiro Yagami.
Kira needs a face and
a name in order to kill.
You should already know that.
Don't say your name so casually.
Also, when you refer to me,
call me Ryuzaki, not L.
This is just another precaution.
Now then. come in...
Now then...
It's been a month since the live
investigation we performed on TV.
Let's sort out the things that
have happened since then.
First. December 10.
Twenty-three criminals in prisons across
the country were killed
one by one, at exactly every hour
after the previous death...
Since students are too preoccupied
during the day,
the times of death almost convinced me
that Kira wasn't a student...
But this made me realize
two major things.
One is that Kira can freely control
his victim's time of death.
And the other...
is that Kira is childish and
hates to lose.
Huh? You're not using
the Death Note today.
Are you studying for
those entrance exams?
It's useless to study
for those at this point.
Hmm. So what are you doing?
Here's the problem.
On December 14.
twelve FBI investigators entered Japan...
to investigate Kira.
And on the 27th...
they all died.
I've done a lot during this period.
Shibuya - Shinagawa
Mr. Raye Penber,
this is Kira.
I've looked you up.
If you deviate even the slightest
from my instructions,
I will kill your entire family.
You included, of course...
What is this?!
Your superior will send you
a file soon.
The file contains the names and faces...
of the FBI investigators who
entered Japan.
Look closely at
each investigator's face as you...
write their names onto
the envelope.
Good bye, Raye Penber.
I handed him...
the Death Note with causes of death
already written in it.
Raye Penber, you're the one...
who killed your colleagues.
Yes. it's me.
Sorry, but could you do that for me?
Yagami
All right, I got it.
I'll get it sent over immediately.
Sayu... could you do me
a small favor?
What..? Right now?
Your father's been pulling all-nighters
without a change of clothes.
Take some over to him.
I've promised my friends that
I'd go to hatsumoude with them.
I'll go.
I need a change of pace.
How lucky!
Thanks, big brother.
Say...
It's true that you were
a splendid FBI investigator.
But right now,
you're just my fiancée...
Don't discuss the Kira case.
Don't do anything dangerous.
That's what we agreed on...
when I took you with me
so we could meet your parents.
All right, Raye.
It's force of habit. Sorry.
Oh... Sorry.
Don't let it bother you so much...
Once we have a family,
you'll be so busy that you'll forget
about your time as an investigator.
There'll be no time for such habits.
Kasumigaseki
Raye...
died.
National Public Safety Committee
Police Department
No...
He was killed by Kira...
- The number you have called...
- cannot be reached at the moment.
- How unusual for Dad.
National Public Safety Committee
Police Department
I wonder if he's at
an important meeting...
I beg you!
I need to meet someone from
investigation headquarters in person.
It concerns something important
about the Kira case.
The Kira case..?
I'm Light. My father is Soichiro Yagami
of the Detective Bureau.
These are my father's change of clothes,
but he doesn't seem to be here.
Could you hold on to them for him?
Oh, Light, it's been a while.
There's no one at headquarters.
Trust me a little.
I'll tell them for you.
That's no good.
I need to tell them in person.
My father is leading
the Kira investigation.
Would you like to leave
a message with me?
His cell phone is off,
so I can't tell him immediately...
But they're probably busy since
several FBI agents were killed and
there have been a lot of investigators
quitting the case out of fear of Kira.
Light, you shouldn't tell those sorts
of things to civilians...
There are already rumors about it.
Besides, she's trustworthy.
I can tell by looking at her eyes.
She's a very wise and
careful person.
You really are brave.
You're trying to get involved
in the Kira case.
Not really...
Umm, may I ask what your name is?
I'm Light Yagami.
It's written as "moon," but read as Light,
with "night" and " God."
I'm Shoko Maki.
"shining," with ko as in " child,"
and "space" with ki as in " tree."
Ms. Maki, right?
Ms. Maki. I think that
Kira's power is...
the ability to control his victims
before he kills them.
Yes. And he probably needs a face
and a name in order to kill.
Yes. Kira probably found out
the names and faces
of the FBI agents in some way...
and killed them.
Yes. My fiancé was one of them.
Upon inspecting the surveillance footage
taken the day he died...
I noticed that he had left
the envelope he had with him
at the ticket booth and the platform
on the train.
Kira probably took the file
concerning the FBI agents
on the train and killed them.
When Raye died,
he was desperately trying
to look into the train.
Kira was probably there.
In other words.
the person in the train that
Raye was looking at was Kira!
Good work, everyone.
Th-This is Watari..?
Umm, what happened to
the clothes you usually wear?
That look gives away the fact
that I am Watari...
It'll let people know
that Ryuzaki is in this hotel...
I-I see.
However she came to
her conclusions...
this woman knows the truth.
I've got to get rid of her.
What's wrong?
Oh, nothing...
I reexamined what you just told me
and I'm beginning to think
that we should quickly investigate
that line of thought.
R-Really?
Yes... Have you told this
to anyone else?
No. You're the first.
You're lucky.
But how are you going to get rid of her?
Can't do it right here and now.
You don't need to tell me that.
I've already thought about that.
Oh. how bold.
Could you tell me the day and time
your fiancé rode the train?
December 27. 15:13.
The Yamanote Line from
Shinjuku to Shibuya.
December 27...
The Yamanote Line to Shibuya...
Yes.
Shoko Maki Suicide January 1, 2007
From 1:15 PM.
so that you don't trouble anyone,
think of a place where nobody
will find your body,
and decide on the best way
to kill yourself.
Commit suicide within forty-eight hours.
Ten more seconds until 1.15...
Now hurry to your death.
What's wrong?
The time's already past.
This is odd.
Why isn't this woman moving?
An alias!
An alias. That's got to be it!
Ryuk can see
the woman's real name.
This is bad...
It's difficult to get someone
to reveal their real name
once they're given an alias...
Light, I can perform
the eye bargain any time.
Yes, the bargain to give you
Shinigami's eyes
which will allow you to
see people's names...
It's no different than
putting in contacts.
It'll only take a few seconds.
I won't halve my remaining lifespan
over this woman.
Don't interfere.
Be quiet, Shinigami!
- Pardon...
- Yes?
Actually, there's something
I still haven't told you.
Okay...
It's impossible to talk to anyone
from headquarters in person.
Huh?
The Kira investigation team
has a system
that prevents anyone from
knowing who's in charge.
I knew you'd say something clever, Light.
Why do you know so much
about them?
I guess it can't be helped.
I'll tell you.
I'm a member of the investigative team.
You're a member of
the investigative team?
L was troubled by the lack
of members on the team.
Everyone had quit because
they were afraid of Kira.
I'm still a high school student...
but I've assisted the police in solving
two cases in the past.
And he was impressed by that..?
Yes.
I see... That makes sense...
Actually, two years ago
I also worked with L
on a certain case in America.
You worked with L?
Until just three months ago,
I was an FBI investigator.
This is it... I can use this.
So that's it.
No wonder. You don't have the attitude
and demeanor
of an amateur detective.
I've decided that I should
approach this in my own way.
I must suspect the police and
even the people on
the investigation team.
But I can believe L.
I sense something in you...
that is similar to L.
Shall we investigate
this case together?
Would you like to be a member
of the investigative team as well?
Of course, not everyone can join.
Yes, we need someone like you.
You should be doing more than
just gathering general information.
I feel it was fate to meet you here!
I shall recommend you!
Oh, sorry, I got a bit excited...
But you're still young and beautiful.
I can't let you take on such
a dangerous investigation...
No! I don't have anything to lose.
I want to catch Kira!
That is all I want to do!
Please let me join your investigation!
That's good.
Then could I see something that may
act as personal identification?
Would a Japanese driver's license
be all right?
Yes.
I made it in time...
Umm, why are you concerned
about the time?
Oh... this? Well. that's because...
I'm Kira.
What's wrong?
There's something that I have to do.
Good bye, Ms. Naomi Misora.
Yes. Yes. Please wait one moment.
Ryuzaki. Mr. Ukita,
from the police department...
Is now taking a phone call concerning
some curious information.
Raye Penber's fiancée?
Naomi Misora...
I've heard that name somewhere...
It's her... She's from the Los Angeles
BB murder case.
She disappeared the day after
the death of her fiancé...
Anyone would be depressed
if their fiancé died.
You don't think that she...
...killed herself?
No. the Naomi Misora I knew
was an excellent.
strong-willed FBI investigator.
She's probably thinking
of catching Kira.
It seems that she was with Penber.
She might have figured something out.
If that's the case,
did Kira get to her first?
Everyone, from here on,
we're only going to investigate
the people that Raye Penber
was investigating in Japan.
He was investigating two people
in relation to the police
and the people around them...
Who are they?
Who are those two?
Vice-Chief Kitamura and
his family, and...
Bureau Chief Yagami and his family.
I also wish to...
place wiretaps and surveillance cameras
in both households.
See you later, Light.
All right. See you tomorrow.
What's this? No one's home?
I'm home...
Say, Light, no one seems to be home.
Let's play a game.
We haven't in a while.
Are you listening?
I-It can't be...
I never knew that
he was doing that..!
Does he have something in his room
that he doesn't want anyone to see?
It's not that strange if
you consider that he's seventeen.
I used to do that for no reason at all.
Hey, Light.
You've been ignoring me.
I'm getting angry.
- No wiretaps planted on these clothes.
- Hey, Light!
Light!
Ryuk, there's a possibility that
there are surveillance cameras
or wiretaps in the house...
No, it's probably both.
Whenever I close my room door,
I always leave the door knob
five millimeters below
its highest position.
In other words.
when I open the door,
if the knob is all the way up,
there's a possibility that someone
has been in my room.
Are you sure it wasn't your parents?
My parents and my sister wouldn't
even notice the slip of paper.
It's suspicious that someone
would take the time
to place the piece of paper
back where it was.
By the way, Ryuk,
what will you do about your apples?
Apples?
Shinigami don't die,
so they don't starve.
In other words, there's no problem
if I don't give you apples.
H-Hold on a second, Light!
Apples are like...
W-Well... like alcohol and cigarettes
are to humans.
I get withdrawal symptoms
if I don't have any for a while.
If you really want to eat apples...
find the location of all the cameras.
There may be a place
where you can eat apples.
Let's go, Ryuk.
Okay! Finding cameras.
This is also amusing!
I love you.
Hideki Ryuga, you're so dreamy!
There's nobody in my classes like him!
At all!
Sayu, eat your dinner.
Later.
Mr. Aizawa. are the Kitamuras
watching television now?
Yes.
Aside from the second eldest,
four of them are watching
television as they eat.
It's channel four.
Watari. order various television stations
to broadcast our transcription.
All right.
NKK News Flash
That's right. I...
Huh? What..?
"In response to the Kira murders,
Interpol has decided to dispatch
"1,500 investigators from
various countries to Japan."
1,500 investigators?
L... He's using the same method
as the first time.
Interpol is silly.
Huh?
There's no point in making
this announcement.
If they're going to send them in,
they should let them come in
and investigate in secret.
Even undercover FBI investigators
met untimely ends.
These investigators could
meet the same fate.
This is just an overblown
attempt by the police
to shock Kira into exposing himself.
But this probably looks suspicious
to Kira.
Your son is very smart.
Huh? Yes. he is.
L-Light... I found all of the cameras.
Shinigami sure get tired
when they try hard...
I'll explain now.
It's a pain to explain
so listen well.
There are an amazing number
of cameras.
I can only think that the guy who placed
them expected some to be found.
There are sixty-four in all.
So where can I eat apples
in this situation?
It's impossible, Ryuk...
Oh, you can't talk to me in the house...
Tell me tomorrow when we go outside.
Okay. This problem is also correct.
Judging from the number of cameras
and their placement,
he's planning on making his decision
in a short amount of time...
A normal person would
give himself away,
but things won't be so easy
against me, L.
Just you watch!
I've written in the Death note
so criminals die for
the next three weeks...
Kira has shown that he can control
his victim's time of death...
So in this case,
Criminals being newly broadcast
have to die when I haven't
had any knowledge of them.
This is bad.
It's my withdrawal symptoms!
I'm going to do this, L!
With Ryuk's information
and prior planning...
I can kill criminals being broadcast,
while masquerading
as a regular exam student!
I'll solve equations with my right hand...
and write names with my left.
Suspect: Takichi Murao
I'll take a potato chip...
and eat it!
After dinner, your son didn't
watch TV or use the computer.
He's just studying...
That's because it's less than
ten days until the Center Test...
Now a criminal whom
I shouldn't know about
will die of a heart attack
in forty seconds.
L himself will be a witness to my alibi.
Just now, a bank clerk suspected
of embezzlement
died of a heart attack
during questioning.
He was shown for the first time
today on the nine o' clock news.
It's Kira!
Today, Kira killed people with light crimes
as soon as they were broadcast...
Even if it is the first day
since the cameras were placed,
the Yagami household
is interestingly in the clear.
Next is the Naomi Misora incident...
Shouldn't we begin
a public investigation?
If we are to do that. it should be done
separately from the Kira case.
We should avoid releasing photographs
and use sketches of her instead.
Ryuzaki.
Turn the channel to Sakura TV.
Something terrible is happening.
In other words,
we are all Kira's hostages.
It is also our duty as broadcasters
to make you this announcement.
Please understand that
this is not a hoax and
- that this is not a publicity stunt.
- Kira's hostages?
What is this?
Four days ago,
our program director was
sent these four tapes.
- These are ummistakenly from Kira.
- Sixty percent ratings?
No, it'll go up to seventy percent.
A tape that proves he is Kira
by predicting killings,
Message
Four videotapes
and another with a message
to the people of the world.
Do you suppose it's just
another fake documentary?
It couldn't be.
Who would make such a nasty fake?
Now, take a look.
I am Kira.
If this video is aired on
April 18, at exactly 5.59 PM,
the time now is 5.59.47...
48... 49...
Please change
the channel to Taiyo TV.
The main newscaster,
Mr. Kazuhiko Hibima
will die of a heart attack
at exactly six o'clock.
Change it!
- Hey!
- Someone!
It can't be!
Something bad will happen
if we don't stop this broadcast!
Get Sakura TV on the line!
It's no good.
No one I know at the station
has their cell phones on.
The lines at the station
are all busy..!
Crap..!
Mr. Ukita!
I'll go to the station and
stop this at the source!
Everyone, please listen to me.
I don't want to kill innocents.
I intend to
create a world without evil.
If everyone cooperates,
this will be simple.
Crap!
If no one tries to catch me,
innocents will not die.
Please be patient.
I will change this corrupt world
into a new one...
ruled by benevolence.
Crap! It's closed!
This is the police!
Open up!
Idiot..!
- We interrupt scheduled programming...
- Hello?
- to go live to the front of Sakura TV.
- Crap! I'm not getting through!
M-Mr. Aizawa!
Take a look!
Someone has collapsed here!
- This is at the entrance of Sakura TV!
- M-Mr. Ukita!
Mr. Aizawa.
Where do you think you're going?
Where Ukita is. of course!
That wouldn't be good.
Please think about this calmly.
I thought that Kira couldn't kill
unless he had a name!
Has Kira discovered that
our names are aliases?!
That may be so.
I deduced that he needed a face
and a name to kill.
But from what I can see.
it's not entirely impossible that
he may only need a face to kill...
All I can say is that Kira is
within that TV station building,
or is in a place where he can watch
who enters the building.
If Kira is in the area. isn't that
more of a reason to go?!
He may have only placed
surveillance cameras in the area.
R-Ryuzaki!
What in the world is this?!
Where is the studio where
they're airing the Kira video?!
There's been a crash!
A vehicle has just crashed into
the Sakura TV studio!
That's one way to get into
the building without being seen.
But who would?
This is the police!
Stop this program!
Wh-What's this?!
Stop the Kira tape immediately!
W-Wait a second. detective!
If you stop this, Kira will kill us...
Bring them out!
If you give them to me now,
you won't be killed!
It's from Bureau Chief Yagami.
Call him back
and give the phone to me.
Quickly, get me Ryuzaki!
It's me.
So that was you
in the patrol wagon, Mr. Yagami.
Yes... I just couldn't take it anymore...
I've confiscated all the tapes.
I'll bring them to you.
God is truly on my side...
But this time. instead of God.
it's a Shinigami.
So it seems.
He probably has the Shinigami eyes...
In other words.
he's a far deadlier Kira than I am...
A second Kira!
Yes. There is a high possibility
that this Kira is pretending
to be Kira.
In other words. we should refer
to him as "Second Kira."
If the impostor slips up and gets caught,
the police might find out about
the Death Note. That would be disastrous.
I can't leave him alone
for too long.
What I need to do
most now is...
to cooperate with the investigation...
and to figure out L's moves
and the fake Kira's moves...
Mr. Yagami.
May I ask your son to help us
with this investigation?
Does that mean
he's no longer a suspect?
If we catch one Kira...
I think we'll get a hint as to
how we can catch the other.
Say, Misa.
I gave you the Death Note...
so why don't you use it
for yourself more often?
I am using it for myself.
I believe in what Kira is doing.
I want to know what kind
of person Kira is.
I want to get to know him
in person.
That's a really dangerous game
you're playing.
You might be killed.
Do you understand that?
It's all right.
I'm sure that Kira is kind
to those with pure hearts.
Just in case something happens...
I'm stronger because
I have the eyes!
My father told me
to come here...
Am I early?
An unknown caller?
Yes?
Are you Light Yagami?
That would be me.
This is L.
Today, I would like to discuss
the Kira incident.
I had your father ask you
to come here.
I'm sorry for doing this
at such a busy time.
It's all right.
I shall lead you to me.
I'm L. Thank you for coming today.
It's all right, L.
I've respected your abilities
for quite some time now.
I see. I'm honored.
Refer to me as Ryuzaki
while you're here.
On to business.
I want you to watch a video.
Please have a seat.
All right, Ryuzaki.
Now then...
It isn't starting.
Oh, I forgot.
Please begin.
This was that tape that was aired...
No. It's a different one.
We believe that this Kira
is a different Kira.
Just the other day, we posed as
the real Kira
and released a message
to the impostor.
I am the real Kira.
To the person
who has used my name.
I shall punish you if you continue
to cause trouble.
Did you see this one?
Yes. So it was a video
made by the police.
This is the response to our message.
It's a bit incomprehensible...
Kira, thank you for
your response.
I shall do as you say.
I want to see you.
What's this?
What is he thinking..?
I don't think you have the eyes...
But I won't kill you. Don't worry.
Is he stupid?!
He talked about the Shinigami Eyes...
- Let me know how we can meet.
- No, don't panic.
When we do,
we can confirm our identities
by showing our Shinigami
to each other.
It's no good.
I have to do something
about him quickly...
What do you think?
I'm surprised...
This Kira seems to care more
about meeting Kira
than about Kira's ideals...
And more importantly,
that word, "Shinigami."
Yes...
That's good...
Yeah. like that..!
That was great...
Just great, Misa.
It was wonderful!
I'm worn out...
Modeling sure uses
a lot of energy!
Say, Rem...
Hmm?
Can I ask you something?
What is it?
Shinigami must each
have a Death Note.
To have a human obtain
and play with a Death Note
requires a Shinigami to
have two Death Notes...
That means that Ryuk, the Shinigami
who gave the Death Note to Kira,
tricked the Shinigami lord into
giving him two notebooks, right?
That's right.
Does that mean you did that, too?
No. The Shinigami lord
is not that easily fooled.
Then how?
I am one of only a few
in the Shinigami World...
Let's just say...
that I know how to kill
a Shinigami.
There once was a Shinigami
named Gelus
who used to watch a certain girl
from the Shinigami World...
I love you more than
anyone else in the world!
I'm always watching you!
I want to protect you!
H-Hey. Stop!
Gelus did something that
a Shinigami should not do.
Gelus used his Death Note
to save the girl.
But that was not good...
Shinigami shorten humans' lives...
They only exist to take them...
At that moment,
Gelus became something which
was neither sand nor rust. and died.
Only his Death Note was left.
Does that mean that
the Shinigami wouldn't have died
if he hadn't fallen in love with that girl?
That's right.
Then...
the Shinigami named Gelus
was the one who saved me...
I see. In order to kill a Shinigami,
you need him to fall in love with a human
and have him save that person.
Now I have something
I can tell Kira.
I wonder if he knows...
how to kill a Shinigami?
P-Pleased to meet you...
I'm Misa Amane.
I thought you might be worried
if you were watching TV...
I just couldn't take it any more.
Take this notebook...
A Death Note...
A Shinigami!
It's Fake Kira...
Have a seat.
Th-Thank you.
How did you find me?
Oh... I thought so.
You haven't made the eye bargain.
When you have the Shinigami eyes,
you can see
a person's lifespan and age.
But you cannot see the lifespan
of someone
who has a Death Note.
Found you.
Yagami... Tsuki, is it?
He's the only one whose lifespan
I can't see.
Light Yagami
He's Kira!
I didn't think it would be
so easy to find him.
Well. I understand that. but...
What would happen
if you were caught by the police
and Kira's secret was discovered?
It's all right...
I wasn't caught and if
I continue to do as you say,
I won't be.
Right?
And I can see L's name...
I will be your eyes...
So...
So?
Make me your girlfriend!
Girlfriend?!
Yes...
If I treat her badly,
she might kill me...
But...
It's impossible.
The tapes you sent to
the television station
all had the same fingerprints
on them.
Those aren't my fingerprints.
I, at least, think before doing things.
If you really don't believe me...
you can hold on to
my Death Note.
Now I can't kill you.
And you can kill me once
I'm of no use to you.
Why is she going this far?
But you might have removed
several pages from the Death Note
and hid them somewhere.
Why are you so suspicious?!
I'm perfectly happy to be used by you!
Believe me!
How can you go so far
as to say that?
About a year ago,
a burglar killed my parents
right in front of me.
I couldn't forgive him...
But the trial dragged along
and he was even looking
at an acquittal...
That's when Kira punished him.
Kira means everything to me.
I just... I just wanted to
meet you so badly...
I wanted to thank you...
All right...
I can't be your boyfriend,
but I can act as if I am.
Those eyes for which
you gave up half of your life
will serve me as a weapon.
Thank you...
I'll try to make you love me.
That's not true.
I just have a knack for
getting things done.
Oh! Yagami.
Hello.
What's wrong, Ryuzaki?
Is it all right for you
to come out here?
I'm all right as long as
you're not Kira.
I forgot to tell you
that I still think that
you might be Kira.
Well, even so, there's only
a five-percent chance that you are him...
And you're the only person
outside now
who knows that I'm L...
I've told everyone on
the investigative team...
that if I die soon, you're Kira.
He weakened my resolve
as soon as I was going to kill him...
This is exactly what he wants...
Light, there you are!
I came because
we were filming nearby.
Misa! You idiot...
Is this a friend of yours?
He's wonderfully individualistic...
No! I've won!
Misa can see Ryuzaki's real name!
I'm Light's girlfriend, Misa Amane.
Pleased to meet you.
I'm Hideki Ryuga.
Huh? Hideki Ryuga?
Yeah. He has the same first name
and last name as that pop idol.
Isn't that amusing?
But that's not the name I see...
Ryuzaki, coming out here
has backfired on you!
Why is he laughing?
Does this mean he noticed?
But if he's guessed that
she's the Second Kira,
there's no way
he would be laughing...
Yagami...
I'm jealous.
You're Misa, the pop idol
from the October edition of Eighteen.
I'm a fan.
What? Really? I'm so happy!
Hey, that girl.
Isn't she Misa-Misa?!
It's true. It's Misa-Misa!
- What? Misa-Misa?
- The real one?!
I should've known I'd be recognized
where there are lots of young people.
I watch you every month.
Keep up the good work.
Yeah. Thank you.
I'll give it my best...
What's going on?
Misa!
It's already time!
Do you want to be late again?!
Oh, sorry, Yoshi.
Let's go!
Oh, okay.
That's good...
Once Misa's out of here,
I just have to give her a call
and ask her for L's name.
See you after work, Light...
Now then, shall we go, Yagami?
Well...
I have a lecture soon.
Could we talk later?
I see. Well then, see you later...
It's over...
It's been fun... L.
Yes?
Yes. I see. We did it.
All right.
The news I have to tell you
is both good and bad...
We've taken Misa Amane
into custody
under suspicion of
being the Second Kira.
How long has he known
about Misa?
There were hairs and fabric threads.
among other things...
on the masking tape used to wrap
the tapes sent by the Second Kira
which matched samples
from her room.
There will probably be a riot
if we accuse her of
being the Second Kira.
So we're saying that her manager
surrendered voluntarily
on charges of drug possession.
The truth will probably
never become public.
R-Ryuzaki!
What is this?!
I've apprehended her
as the Second Kira.
It's necessary, at the very least.
Also, Mr. Yagami...
I'm probably going to have
to bring in Light to testify as Kira.
Please be prepared.
Oh. Rem.
Light Yagami...
Misa forfeited her ownership
of the Death Note.
All of her memories concerning
the notebook have been erased.
She no longer can reveal
your secret...
Misa even refused my offer
to help her escape.
She probably figured that
she would be causing you trouble
if they thought she
had special powers...
She did it because she wants
you to love her.
Light Yagami...
I'll kill you if you don't save Misa.
It's been a week
since we've detained Amane
and Light Yagami...
Kira has completely
stopped killing criminals...
We're pretty sure that
they're Kira...
But why did Light accept
his detention so peacefully?
Even if he were Kira,
did he think he could act
as if he knew nothing?
It's not like Light Yagami...
No, it's not like Kira.
Light...
It's been just one week...
But I'm pretty sure
you're worn out...
Are you all right?
Now that I've come this far,
I think it's about time...
Yeah. I don't think I look
very cool in this situation...
But I'm going to discard...
Such worthless pride.
Got it.
See you later.
Why am I doing this?
Ryuzaki...
I did indeed agree to be detained
and chose to do this...
But I just realized that
doing this is meaningless!
Why? Because I'm not Kira!
Get me out of here quickly!
What's wrong, Light Yagami?
What you're saying is crazy...
But... for some reason it feels
like it's the truth.
Let me out of here quickly.
This is a waste of time.
No. I can't let you out.
You're wrong.
I can understand why
you deduced
from the investigative situation
that I'm Kira, but it's a trap!
I'm not Kira!
Zoom in or something and
look at my eyes!
Are these the eyes of
someone who is lying?
Misa Amane...
Mr. Stalker. what is it?
Are you planning to let me go?
Do you know why
you're being detained here?
Why? Is it because
I'm a pop idol?
But you're the first stalker
who's gone this far.
So you really don't know
who Kira is?
Huh?
This again?
That's what I want to know.
Wh-What's going on?
Since yesterday, criminals are
suddenly dying again
after more than two weeks
of nothing.
Yeah.
Kira Returns
It's the return of Kira.
I don't know what's going on...
Isn't it great that Light and Misa-Misa
can return to their normal lives?
They're still under surveillance, though.
Matsuda, stop calling
her Misa-Misa.
Say... This doesn't really
feel like a date.
Even though I asked you to help
with the investigation,
you and Light are still suspects.
Please put up with this.
Anyway, you don't seem
very enthusiastic
despite the fact that we're helping
with the investigation.
Enthusiasm?
I have none...
Actually, I'm depressed.
You're depressed?
Yes.
All this time.
I had thought that you were Kira.
I'm shocked that my deduction
was off...
Ryuzaki...
What?!
That hurt.
Stop messing around.
I wasn't Kira...
so you don't feel like
doing anything
because your deduction
was wrong?
I may have phrased that incorrectly.
It would be a waste for us
to make a move.
so we shouldn't...
There's no way
we can catch him
if we don't chase him!
Do you know how
many innocent people
you've involved in this case?!
Besides that, you're the one
that detained Misa and me!
I know...
But whatever your reasons...
It's an eye for an eye.
Oh?!
It's not that my deduction was wrong,
but the case isn't solved with
Light equals Kira and
Misa Amane equals Second Kira.
So I was a bit depressed.
Is it wrong for someone
to feel like that?
That's no good.
The way you talk...
It's as if you want me
to be Kira.
I want you to be Kira?
That may be true...
I just noticed... now...
I wanted you to be Kira...
It's an eye... for an eye.
I'm pretty strong.
L-Let's call the room
and stop them!
- Yes?
- Ryuzaki, listen to this.
Misa-Misa became number one
in Eighteen's reader popularity poll!
Yes, I see...
That means that she's the heroine
in the next Nishinaka film!
What's wrong?
Matsuda's acting stupid again.
Well, Matsuda is a natural at that.
I can hear you...
Ryuzaki, I'm sorry
you don't feel like doing anything,
but come over here for a second.
Take a good look at this.
Don't you think this is peculiar?
All three of them were
prominent Japanese businessmen.
They all died of heart attacks.
As a result,
Yotsuba's stock prices rose
and those of other companies dropped.
In other words, they're deaths
which are in Yotsuba's favor...
What do you think?
I don't think that Kira is
supporting Yotsuba, but...
It seems we're all here.
Then let's begin our regular meeting.
To further the growth of
the Yotsuba Group...
to become the biggest business
in the world...
Who should we kill?
Ryuzaki.
What is it. Watari?
Detective Eraldo Coil has received
a request to reveal L's identity.
Wasn't Eraldo Coil...
the man who's the
next greatest detective after L?
Who in the world would send
such a request?
The person who sent
in the request is...
Masahiko Kida. the head of
Yotsuba Group's Planning Department
in their Tokyo headquarters.
So it was Yotsuba!
That's not good.
We're short-handed.
We need to pay attention
to Coil. too?
It's all right. The detective known
as Eraldo Coil is me.
The world's three greatest detectives,
L. Coil. and Danuve...
are all me.
I'll give you this strawberry,
so keep it a secret.
You're really something, Ryuzaki.
Just watch me. Even I can be useful...
Okay. I just have to get close
to him, right?
Leave it to me.
And I just have to break
the surveillance cameras
and defense system...
of Yotsuba's Tokyo headquarters,
where this guy is.
Yes.
It is safe to assume that Kira and
Yotsuba are connected.
We're going to check Yotsuba
to see how many people
have special powers.
It is important that we have
a clear understanding.
Crap. I can't hear them clearly.
I've got to pick up something important...
He's just in the way.
Let's kill him and split up his stocks.
I just heard them say, "kill"!
Kira sure is varied.
Kira?!
There it is! Kira!
There it is! What?!
"Let's have Kira kill him"?!
I heard it!
They're really working with Kira...
I did it... I did a great job!
Who are you?!
If at all possible, do not do
anything hasty or impulsive.
Don't make any decisions
by yourself.
Ryuzaki...
What is it. Watari?
Mr. Matsuda has sent
an emergency signal
from his belt.
Where's it coming from?
Well. it seems...
it's coming from within
Yotsuba's Tokyo headquarters.
My name is Taro Matsui.
I'm a manager with
Yoshida Productions!
How would you like to use
our top multi-talented star, Misa Amane?
As the face of your company
and for your commercials?!
Matsuda, you idiot...
Light! Are you allowed to
go out with me today?
Along with Ryuzaki...
Misa...
Do you love Light?
Yes...
So...
Who would you pick, Light or Kira?
Huh?
Light, of course.
So would you want to be
of help to Light
and work with him
on the investigation?
R-Ryuzaki!
Yeah! I'll do anything for
Light's sake!
W-Wait a second.
What are you doing?
Right now, Matsuda has
been captured by Yotsuba.
Let's make use of the situation.
Misa will go to Yotsuba and
try to advertise herself.
We will get information
about Yotsuba from Misa.
She'll be our spy.
Yeah.
That's not good.
Why?
Because you'll be put in danger.
Are you worried about me?
Light.
If we win. Misa won't die. And...
as long as we're handcuffed,
we share the same fate.
Back to business...
Let's have Matsuda die.
Misa. head out.
Okay...
I'm Misa-Misa!
I won't go nude, but swimsuits
and underwear are okay!
Pleased to meet you!
She's really cute in person.
That's not the problem right now,
don't you think?
Yes. drink. drink.
This is heaven.
Misa's pretty good.
What's going on?!
Well... I sure am drunk.
Now, everyone...
the thing you've been waiting for!
The Taro Matsui Show!
Hey, what are you doing?
Matsui. do it!
Stop it! It's dangerous!
You idiot!
It's all right...
He fell!
This is bad...
Oh... no!
I came when I heard a thud.
How horrible!
- 119. 119!
- Honestly. What a horrid role.
Everyone,
leave this to us and go home.
Wha..? No way!
It's all right. Please consider
the advertisement offer.
Even if we're short of people,
I didn't want to have to do this.
Matsuda, you idiot...
Even though the meeting's over,
I still have to kill criminals
when I get home.
It sure is tough being Kira.
But it's getting interesting...
I'm going to make
Misa Amane my wife.
Money, power, and a beautiful wife...
People will be jealous of me...
Once we're married...
I'll put a lot of insurance money
on her...
Would she marry such
a crooked guy?
This is tiring...
But it's going well.
I've got to try hard...
Wh-What is this?!
A monster?
Misa, you're in a dangerous situation.
The Yotsuba workers
may kill you.
I came to tell you that.
Calm down and listen to me.
Calm down?
You look more like you would kill me!
I am your ally.
My... ally?
What are you?
I know you aren't a stalker,
but you don't look human at all...
Of course. I'm a Shinigami.
Misa, we once worked together.
I don't know what
you're talking about...
The Death Note...
If you write a person's name in it,
that person dies...
With that notebook.
Light Yagami punished criminals
and became known as Kira.
And you had the same...
no, greater power than Kira.
Light is Kira...
and I'm Second Kira?
Ryuzaki's correct.
When you go back...
you should be able
to tell who's Kira.
Be especially wary of him.
Sorry I took so long
in the restroom.
I fixed up my makeup.
Listen, when you return,
the man who's sitting
in front of me is Kira...
Rem... The person in front
of Rem is Kira...
Higuchi is Kira...
This is really bad...
Kyosuke Higuchi...
He's the dirty old man
who's been sending me
text messages.
It's really bad that this guy
is Kira...
Misa...
Shall we get something to eat?
Don't take me anywhere strange, okay?
Well, even if you do
something funny,
it's all right because
I can kill people.
What are you talking about, Misa?
Is this what Light Yagami
wants you to do?
You say such funny things, Misa.
You can kill people?
It's true. Because I'm...
The Second Kira.
It's my dream to become
Kira's bride.
Kira is sure to need me as well.
If she's the Second Kira...
then it's clear from
the Sakura TV incident
that she has the Shinigami eyes...
But if it is true,
I want to have her by my side.
I'll test her...
Ginzo Kaneboshi.
He's the president of
a major credit consumer business.
He's a crook who's famous
for his cruel collection methods.
Sometimes, he makes people
pay with insurance money.
How about him?
Can you find out immediately
if he died?
I can tell if I make a phone call.
Then turn around for a moment.
Misa...
I have to kill Ginzo Kaneboshi. don't I?
Higuchi will trust you if I do that...
Fine.
Ginzo Kaneboshi
All right. He's dead now.
This is Higuchi of Yotsuba.
Sorry! Our president just collapsed
and stopped breathing...
Call back later!
See?
She killed a person that
I chose right here...
It would have been impossible
unless she had powers!
It's decided!
I'm Kira, you'll marry me, right?!
Prove it.
I can't kill until I go home.
You understand.
Yeah... then it's no good.
It might be a scheme to
lure me into your house.
Oh. I know.
Then stop killing criminals.
If you're Kira,
I'm sure you can do it.
Then begin killing when
I tell you to.
Then I'll believe you.
Killing criminals is something
that only Kira could do.
I see. That's a good idea.
All right.
I'm Kira, so in order to
make you trust me,
I'm going to stop killing criminals
from now.
And when you know I'm Kira,
we'll get married!
And so...
Higuchi is Kira!
It's been three days since
I stopped killing criminals.
That's good enough, isn't it?
Now, if I marry the Second Kira,
Misa Amane...
I'll get the Shinigami eyes.
And I'll control Yotsuba!
Higuchi, this is bad.
Turn on your TV to Sakura TV.
So one of these people
is Kira, right?
Yes. I have a lot of proof.
What is this?
It's probably a hoax.
It's Sakura TV.
At the beginning of the program,
he said that he came across
a meeting of eight people.
I-It's him!
Misa's manager...
I think his name was Matsui!
Why is he alive?!
Are you all right?
Shall we stop?
No... I'm well aware of the danger...
Even if I'm killed, I shall fight on...
until the end in the name
of justice.
That's good. That's good.
Don't make
the Kira announcement
until the end of the program.
This is bad.
- I don't know when he'll expose me.
- The announcement will come soon.
Don't change your channel.
Cosme Misa.
A devilish charm...
An angel's glitter...
Misa's winning rouge...
Mido. it's me.
Something bad is happening
on Sakura TV.
Get your father in
the House of Councilors and
have the Ministry of Public Management
stop the program.
I'm watching,
but that's impossible.
No one trusts this program
and is suspicious of it.
Besides, there's nothing
to fear any more.
That guy revealed his face...
We can confirm that
it's Taro Matsui.
Namikawa is telling everyone
to watch this show.
One of the seven of us is Kira.
Soon. Taro Matsui will die.
I see. I'm the only one
who knows
that Taro Matsui is not
his real name, so...
If I say that,
then I'll reveal that I'm Kira.
- You're right. Talk to you later.
- Kira will be revealed shortly!
Stay with us!
If he's going to say it at
the end of the program,
I still have two hours...
I've confirmed Higuchi.
He's only got a bag on him.
I'm going after him.
Everything's going according
to plan, isn't it?
Yes.
Taichiro Yamashita
Now, how are you going to kill?
Show me!
Taichiro Yamashita
It's no good.
He just made a note of his name
and is leaving.
He's not going to kill him here?
Ryuzaki! Shall I restrain him?
I still don't know how he kills.
He might do something in his car.
Turn monitor one to Higuchi's car.
Higuchi is awfully calm
despite wanting to kill Matsuda
as soon as possible...
36... 37...
38... 39...
40 seconds...
Kira is a murderer,
so I won't forgive him.
Crap! He won't die!
What's the meaning of this?!
He said. "He won't die!"
Did he try to kill him already?
Is writing his name all he has to do?
Rem. Let's bargain.
Bargain?
Could Kira's power be
from heaven or something?
At any rate, we should watch him.
Now I'm unstoppable...
With this, I have unlimited options.
I'm going after him!
Stop the Porsche.
Pull over to the side of the road.
This is bad.
Higuchi has been caught
by a motorcycle policeman.
You were speeding.
Show me your driver's license!
Yeah... all right.
All screens on Higuchi's car...
Where did I put my license...
I have no time
to be sticking around here.
H-Hey!
Higuchi has ditched
the motorcycle policeman and is escaping!
This is traffic riot squad...
Th-The motorcycle policeman
rear-ended a truck!
It's a collision!
A collision?!
An accidental death?
This is bad.
No, that aside,
how did he obtain the name
of that motorcycle policeman?
Could it be that he killed him
by looking at his face like Second Kira?
Rem... Bargain...
No... If he could kill just by
looking at someone's face...
he would have killed
Matsuda already.
What's going on? But...
Everyone!
It's too dangerous to leave
Higuchi alone any longer.
We will proceed to capture him.
Higuchi is now able to kill
by looking at someone's face,
like Second Kira.
We will capture him with
that in mind!
This is L.
We have narrowed down
Kira to a single person.
Currently, he's heading
from Hibiya to Shibuya
on highway Route One
in a red Porsche 911.
We shall capture him.
Instruct all officers
not to approach that Porsche.
Dad. after the next commercial.
take measure seven.
Got it.
Then Yagami, shall we go?
Yeah.
Dad...
Higuchi is almost at Sakura TV.
He'll be there in less than
fifteen minutes.
Are you all right?
I don't want my son
asking me if I'm all right.
I'm all right, Light.
We're getting lots of...
phone calls and faxes
showing support...
for you, the brave witness.
I'm very sorry...
What?!
But due to circumstances,
- we will end the program here.
- A mannequin?! No way!
Stop right there, Higuchi!
Don't move!
Give up.
Y-You must be making
some kind of mistake.
I had something I wanted to
talk to Demegawa about...
I'll show you my card...
Bureau Chief!
Higuchi has a gun!
The Bureau Chief has been shot.
Higuchi is getting away!
I'm all right.
We have no choice.
We shall proceed to
capture him as well.
Watari, are you ready?
Yes...
That's as far as you're going.
Don't come any closer!
Nobody come near me!
It's over...
Yes. it is...
Higuchi... How do you kill people?
The notebook.
Notebook?
You may not believe me,
but if I write the name
of someone whose face
I know in that notebook.
that person will die.
Notebook...
Yagami.
Yeah, there is one in Higuchi's bag.
It has names in it.
but it looks like
any other notebook...
What's wrong, Dad?
Oh... uh...
I-It seems only people who have touched
this notebook can see this...
T-This monster!
It's a Shinigami... isn't it?
They... really... do... exist...
Light Yagami... Amane...
May 22, Aoyama...
Show notebooks. Love at first sight.
Second Kira...
Ryuzaki, let me see the notebook.
Method of killing.
Kira... Second... Two!
There are more than
two notebooks in existence!
This isn't over yet...
I am L.
A-Are you all right?
Anyone would be surprised
by that monster...
Ryuzaki.
Yes?
I'm going to cross-check
the names written in here...
with the names of the victims.
Huh? Yes...
Well, you're right.
I've won!
It's just as I planned.
Higuchi?!
Ryuzaki, Higuchi is!
Wh-What's this?!
What's going on?!
Hey, Higuchi!
Wh-What are you doing, Dad?!
If Higuchi dies, now...
I-It can't be..!
No, but, he's already...
Yeah, he's dead.
You're next...
Ryuzaki.
Light, I remember.
I remember all about
when I used this notebook.
Misa, your memory
should have returned
when you read this message.
A letter from Light!
Do you remember
my friend at To-Oh University
who went by the name
Hideki Ryuga?
I want you to write his name
in the notebook and kill him.
Burn this letter.
Hide a few pages of
the notebook with you...
And bury the notebook.
When you meet me again,
let me touch a clipping of
the notebook in a natural way.
If you do this,
I'll love you for
the rest of my life.
All right!
I see. This is Light's plan!
He wanted me to get this notebook,
regain my memory...
And kill Hideki Ryuga...
Ryuzaki...
One of Light's obstacles
has disappeared
and I can help him.
It's no good... Light...
I can't remember his name.
I've seen dozens and hundreds
of names and life spans...
I just can't remember!
I'm so stupid!
I can finally come back.
Ryuk!
It's been a while...
How are you?
Sorry, but...
I'm still male.
You're making me bashful.
It looks like things went well.
He planned to relinquish ownership
of the notebook.
lose his memory and
regain it once more
by touching the notebook...
Rem would haunt someone else...
and wait for Light to find her.
For Light to find her...
The police have seen
the notebook
and the fake rules that
Light had me write.
They're pouring over them
right now...
Now. Rem...
Whoever writes a name
in the notebook will die
unless he writes another name
in the notebook
within 13 days, right?
Wha..?
Which means that...
Light and Misa-Misa are
completely cleared!
Yes. indeed...
Light and Amane were detained
for more than fifty days
and are still under surveillance...
There's no way they'd still
be alive if they're both Kira.
Light pulled it off really well...
Oh yeah...
Here.
Light told me to bring this.
Is it really that delicious?
Yeah. Apples of the Human World
are juicy..?
Is that what you'd say?
At any rate, they're great.
Do you want to eat?
It's an apple from the Shinigami World.
It doesn't look very good...
Come on, just one bite.
Oh yeah, Ryuk...
Do the eye bargain with me.
Sand!
A bargain, huh?
You understand, don't you?
You've made a bargain
with Rem once before.
Do you really want to halve
your life a second time?
Well, that can't be helped...
I've forgotten the name
I had to remember...
Light will be angry with me
if I don't take a look at it again.
Well, I'm okay with that...
Oh. it's Misa-Misa.
Ryuk!
Why is he haunting Misa?
Misa's life has been halved
once more!
Did she... do the eye bargain with Ryuk?!
Light...
It's been a while, Ryuk.
Misa, right now,
I feel like living with you
in my ideal new world for
a long, long time.
Light, I'm so happy!
Misa. let's make
a new crimeless world together.
One with only kind and
innocent people in it.
Yeah!
What's wrong, Ryuzaki?
What's wrong?
♪ Careful
♪ God is watching.
♪ Please hold my hand
on dark nights.
♪ Even if you're far away
by yourself.
♪ You always find me...
♪ You tell me everything
you know.
♪ Even if I don't remember...
♪ You tell me many times.
♪ But what do I do once
I know everything?
What do you mean?
Criminals are dying again?!
There were fourteen
just yesterday.
They were broadcast
after Higuchi died...
Immediately, huh?
I guess that means that Higuchi
wasn't necessarily Kira...
No. We're positive that Higuchi
was the one killing criminals
until we caught him.
Then does that mean that
another Kira has appeared?
Oh... why?!
Crap... curse you, Kira...
Kira appears now...
What's going on?
Oh no...
There's only Misa...
This happened as soon
as Amane was freed. didn't it?
Ryuzaki, are you still saying that?
Misa is not involved.
It happened as soon
as Higuchi died.
You're right...
Well. if there is another notebook
and someone is using it...
I'll catch him.
The Shinigami told me
he doesn't know, but...
If someone can kill
by writing a name on
a clipping from the notebook...
It's not impossible...
But... whoever writes
a name in this notebook...
has to write another name
within thirteen days or die...
Light Yagami and Misa Amane
are living...
Thirteen days...
It's only that fact...
Ryuzaki, even if we do
catch the person
who was writing in the notebook...
Can we really convict and
punish him for mass murder?
Of course we can!
He wrote countless names
knowing that people would die.
We should kill him
if we don't want the existence
of the notebook to go public.
Killing him isn't a very
level-headed reaction.
but our superiors would probably
take measures like that.
If he admits to killing
with the notebook.
he would receive
the death penalty.
Or at least a life sentence.
Something like that.
What are you thinking,
Light Yagami?
If Misa is caught,
you'd be caught too...
So that's it!
What a bastard!
Light Yagami is sure that
I'll save Misa's life...
In order to save Misa
in this situation,
I have to write Ryuzaki's real name
in my notebook...
And if I kill Ryuzaki...
It'll be something related to
Misa's life and I'll die as well...
Light Yagami is making
everything go his way...
What are you going to do, Rem?
I know full well that
despite being a Shinigami,
you're infatuated with Misa.
Misa's life has been
halved once more.
There's no way
you'd leave her alone.
Think about Misa's happiness.
What are you doing there, Ryuzaki?
What are you doing there, Ryuzaki?!
What are you doing, Ryuzaki?
No... I'm not doing anything
in particular, but...
The sound of the bells...
Bells?
Yes.
I've been hearing noisy bells
throughout the day...
I don't hear anything.
Really? They've been ringing
all day and...
I can't help but be curious...
Do you suppose it's a church?
A wedding?
- Or perhaps...
- What are you talking about, Ryuzaki?
Don't say silly things.
Let's go back.
Sorry.
Everything I say is a lie, so...
Don't believe any of it.
That's right, Ryuzaki.
Most of what you say is a lie.
There would be no end if
I took you seriously all the time.
I know that very well.
Yes, that's right, Light.
But... it's true for both of us.
What do you mean?
Have you ever told the truth
at any point since you were born?
What are you talking about, Ryuzaki?
It's true that I lie once
in a while.
But how many people live
their entire lives
only telling the truth?
Humans aren't perfect.
Everyone lies. Even so...
I've tried not to tell lies
that hurt others.
That's my answer.
I thought you'd say that.
Oh, Ryuzaki!
What is the meaning of this?!
I heard that you got an approval
from a certain country
to use the notebook for
an execution!
Watari...
Good work.
- You're welcome.
- Right off...
Make arrangements
to transport the notebook.
Yes.
Ryuzaki, what's the meaning
of this?
It means that I'm going to
try out the notebook for real.
That's pointless.
We don't have to do that.
We already know that the power
of the notebook is real. don't we?
Besides, who's going
to write the name?
Once you write in the notebook,
you have to continue writing
names every thirteen days!
The one who's going to
write the name
is someone who'll be executed
within thirteen days.
If he's still alive after thirteen days...
We've made a judicial bargain
to exempt him from execution.
- But we can't sacrifice people's lives...
- Just a little more.
If we just clear this up...
We'll solve the case.
Wh-What's this?!
A blackout?!
Watari?
Wata..!
Data deletion?
What's the meaning of this?!
I told Watari to erase
all information...
in the event that something
happens to him.
If something happens?
It can't be...
Where's the Shinigami?
Come to think of it.
I don't see him...
He's not anywhere!
What's the meaning of this?!
Everyone... The Shiniga... mi...
R-Ryuzaki!
What's wrong?!
Hey! Ryuzaki!
Get a hold of yourself!
- What's this?!
- What's going on?
Calm down, Light!
We're going to be killed!
Watari, Ryuzaki, we're next!
Crap.
Where are you, Shinigami?!
Come out!
L-Light!
You should know something!
Come out!
Ryuzaki...
We held your funeral
without informing anyone...
We're going to pretend you're alive
and move the world's police
as if nothing has changed...
We'll catch Kira. I promise you.
Rest in peace...
That's right...
Let's avenge Ryuzaki!
Solving this case will
be our parting gift...
For Watari and the other victims' sake...
And for everyone...
I will get Kira executed.
Light...
Matsuda.
L's finally gone...
I guess I can't expect things to
be very interesting anymore...
Everyone in my way is gone.
Everyone else believes me.
It's only a matter of time before
I control the police!
What do you think, L?
I've completely won!
I win!
Ryuk, you don't expect things
to be very interesting?
That's not true. From here on...
You'll get to observe the making
of a new world.
I am... the god...
of the new world...
Light Yagami
You weren't a god at that moment...
You were more like...
So you're gone...
Go and see...
If you're lucky...
Someone amazing will
pick up the Death Note...
And you'll get to see
something interesting
that you'll never forget.
Isn't that right...
Light?